Hale Family Papers, 1787-1988
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- HALE FAMILY
  - Generation IV
    - Hale, Ellen Day (1855-1940)
      - Correspondence, outgoing
        - Clark, Abigail [secretary to EEH], 1909-12 (Box 73, Folder 1)
        - Curtis, Miss (re: art schools for women in Paris), 1887 (Box 73, Folder 2)
        - Hale groups
          - 1873-Nov 1882 (Box 73, Folder 3-18)
          - Dec 1882-1909 (Box 74, Folder 1-8)
        - "Brother" (unidentified), 1880-83 (Box 74, Folder 9)
        - "Grandmama" (unidentified), 1878-83 (Box 74, Folder 10)
        - Hale, Arthur [brother], 1874-82, 1923 (Box 74, Folder 11)
        - Hale, Edward Everett [father]
          - 1872-95 (Box 74, Folder 12-22)
          - 1896-1909 (Box 75, Folder 1-9)
        - Hale Edward Everett and Emily (Perkins) [parents], 1879-92, undated (Box 75, Folder 10-12)
        - Hale, Edward Everett, Jr. "Jack" [brother], 1873-84 (Box 75, Folder 13)
        - Hale, Emily Perkins [mother]
          - 1872-Jul 1882 (Box 75, Folder 14-18)
          - Sep 1882-1897 (Box 76, Folder 1-20)
          - 1898-1914 (Box 77, Folder 1-8)
        - Hale, Herbert Dudley "Bertie" [brother], 1878-83 (Box 77, Folder 9)
        - Hale, Lilian Westcott [sister-in-law], 1902-39, undated (Box 77, Folder 10-20)
        - Hale, Nancy [niece], 1926 (Box 78, Folder 1)
        - Hale, Philip Leslie [brother], 1878-1928 (Box 78, Folder 2)
        - Hale, Robert Beverly "Robby" "Delancey" [brother], 1877-82 (Box 78, Folder 3)
        - Hale, Susan [aunt], 1886 (Box 78, Folder 4)
        - Miscellaneous, 1878-1924 (Box 78, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence, incoming
        - A, 1891-1935, undated (Box 78, Folder 6)
        - B, 1877-1934, undated (Box 78, Folder 7)
        - Beaux, Cecilia, 1891-1931 (Box 78, Folder 8)
        - Berenson, Mary, 1904 (Box 78, Folder 9)
        - C, 1906-35, undated (Box 78, Folder 10)
        - Clark, Abigail, 1909-17, undated (Box 78, Folder 11-12)
        - Clements, Gabrielle, 1907-33 (Box 78, Folder 13-15)
        - D, 1904-35, undated (Box 78, Folder 16)
        - E, 1874-1933 (Box 78, Folder 17)
        - F, 1910-11, undated (Box 78, Folder 18)
        - Fields, Annie, 1886 (Box 78, Folder 19)
        - G, 1882-1913, undated (Box 78, Folder 20)
        - Garfield, Helen N., 1906-13 (Box 78, Folder 21)
        - H, 1907-34, undated (Box 78, Folder 22)
        - Hall, Betsy, 1908, undated (Box 78, Folder 23)
        - Hoar, George F., 1897 (Box 78, Folder 24)
        - Holman's Print Shop, 1933-35 (Box 78, Folder 25)
        - Hunt, William Morris, 1878, undated (Box 78, Folder 26)
        - I-J, 1905-34, undated (Box 78, Folder 27)
        - Jewett, Sarah Orne, 1891, undated (Box 78, Folder 28)
        - K, 1891-1934, undated (Box 78, Folder 29)
        - Kroll, Genevieve and Leon, 1933-35, undated (Box 78, Folder 30)
        - L, 1881-1933, undated (Box 78, Folder 31)
        - Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1915, 1923 (Box 78, Folder 32)
        - Loring, Helen J., 1915-19 (Box 78, Folder 33)
        - M, 1875-1933, undated (Box 78, Folder 34)
        - N, 1909, 1914 (Box 78, Folder 35)
        - Newell, Annie C., undated (Box 78, Folder 36)
        - Nordhoff, Charles, 1898-1901 (Box 78, Folder 37-38)
        - Nordhoff, Evelyn Hunter, 1891-93 (Box 79, Folder 1-7)
        - Nordhoff, Evelyn Hunter: etchings, sample of leather work, undated (Box 79, Folder 8)
        - Nordhoff, Lida, 1893, undated (Box 79, Folder 9)
        - P-Q, 1912-31, undated (Box 79, Folder 10)
        - Page, Annie, 1908-11, 1931 (Box 79, Folder 11)
        - Page, Lillian A., 1864-65, 1934-35 (Box 79, Folder 12)
        - Park, Charles E., 1928-34 (Box 79, Folder 13)
        - Pinchot, Gifford and Mary, 1911-24, undated (Box 79, Folder 14)
        - R, 1909-25 (Box 79, Folder 15)
        - Ronka, Louis S. and Arne, 1932-35 (Box 79, Folder 16)
        - Roosevelt, Edith Kermit and secretary, 1906 (Box 79, Folder 17)
        - S, 1902-34, undated (Box 79, Folder 18)
        - Seymour, George Dudley, 1921-25 (Box 79, Folder 19)
        - Smith, Maverette G., 1908-12, undated (Box 79, Folder 20)
        - T-W, 1909-33, undated (Box 79, Folder 21)
        - White, Eliza Orne, 1883-1917, 1932-36, undated (Box 79, Folder 22-25)
        - Y, 1911, undated (Box 79, Folder 26)
        - Unidentified and fragments, 1907-33, undated (Box 79, Folder 27)
      - Originals of correspondence to family from Europe, 1881-83. (Box 80-81)
        [USE PHOTOCOPIES IN BOXES 73-77]
      - Speeches and writings
        - Diaries, 1901, 1904, 1905, 1921 (Box 82)
        - Speeches
          - Leonardo da Vinci: text and notes, undated (Box 83, Folder 1)
          - Lucretia P. Hale, the Author of the Peterkins (The Literary Society, Washington, DC, 1926)
            - manuscript (Box 83, Folder 2)
            - typescript (Box 83, Folder 3)
          - William Morris Hunt, undated (Box 83, Folder 4)
          - Sicily, undated (Box 83, Folder 5)
        - Writings
          - Poems, 1891, 1913, undated (Box 83, Folder 6)
          - Epistolary fiction re: Americans in Italy, undated
            - manuscript (Box 83, Folder 7)
            - typescript (Box 83, Folder 8)
          - Miscellaneous: notebook, undated (Box 83, Folder 9)
          - Stories and essays
            - Re: art student in France, undated (Box 83, Folder 10)
            - Re: travelling west in the U.S., undated (Box 83, Folder 11)
            - Re: art students visiting Cape Ann quarries, undated (Box 83, Folder 12)
            - Etching, undated (Box 83, Folder 13)
            - "Christmas Shoes and Stockings," undated (Box 83, Folder 14)
            - "For the Honor of the Class," undated (Box 83, Folder 15)
            - "Lucretia Peabody Hale," circa 1926 (Box 83, Folder 16)
            - "A Pilgrimage to Mont St. Michel," undated (Box 83, Folder 17)
            - "A Week in France," undated (Box 83, Folder 18)
            - Notebook with "story written for her father," a piece about the work of Gabrielle Clements, and Finnish language exercises, undated (Box 83, Folder 19)
          - Published
            - Miscellaneous, 1883, 1890 (Box 83, Folder 20)
            - Articles re: France in Traveller, 1882-85 (Box 83, Folder 21)
            - "History of Art," National Bureau of Unity Clubs leaflet no. 14, 1888 (Box 83, Folder 22)
    - Ellen Day Hale (1855-1940) and Gabrielle Clements De Vaux (1858-1948): correspondence (from others), 1916-32 (Box 84, Folder 1)
    - Gabrielle Clements De Vaux (1858-1948)
      - General, 1948, undated (Box 84, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence
        - General, 1910-38, undated (Box 84, Folder 3)
        - From Ellen Day Hale, 1913-19 (Box 84, Folder 4)
    - Hale, Henry Kidder (1869-76): certificate of baptism, 1869 (Box 85, Folder 1)
    - Hale, Herbert Dudley (1866-1908) "Bertie"
      - Biographical materials and memorabilia
        - Death: condolence letters, 1908 (Box 85, Folder 2)
        - Education
          - General, 1877-91 (Box 85, Folder 3)
          - Harvard College, 1886-88 (Box 85, Folder 4)
        - Notebooks, 1886, undated (Box 85, Folder 5)
        - Scrapbook, undated (Box 85, Folder 6)
        - Drawings, undated (Box 85, Folder 7)
      - Correspondence, outgoing
        - Hale, Edward Everett [father], 1873-1908, undated (Box 85, Folder 8-16)
        - Hale, Edward Everett and Emily (Perkins) [parents], 1884-1906 (Box 86, Folder 1)
        - Hale, Ellen Day [sister], 1876-1904 (Box 86, Folder 2)
        - Hale, Emily (Perkins) [mother], 1873-1908 (Box 86, Folder 3-6)
        - Miscellaneous, 1879-92, undated (Box 86, Folder 7)
      - Correspondence, incoming
        - Miscellaneous, 1886-1902, undated (Box 86, Folder 8)
        - Re: engagement, 1891 (Box 86, Folder 9)
    - Hale, Margaret Curzon (Marquand) (1872-1948) [Mrs. Herbert Dudley Hale]
      - Correspondence, outgoing
        - Hale, Edward Everett [father-in-law], 1891-1902, undated (Box 86, Folder 10)
        - Hale, Edward Everett and Emily (Perkins) [parents-in-law], 1908-09 (Box 86, Folder 11)
        - Hale, Emily (Perkins) [mother-in-law], 1892-1909 (Box 86, Folder 12-14)
        - Miscellaneous Hales, 1902, 1932, undated (Box 86, Folder 15)
      - Family home: Curzon Mill, Newburyport, MA, 1948 (Box 86, Folder 16)
    - Hale, Philip Leslie (1865-1931) and Lilian (Westcott) (1881-1963)
      - Artwork
        [See also Philip Leslie Hale and Lilian Westcott Hale]
        - Clippings, 1911-77 (Box 87, Folder 1)
        - Correspondence 1936-88, undated (Box 87, Folder 2-3)
        - Exhibitions, 1970 (Box 87, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence
        - General, 1928, undated (Box 87, Folder 5)
        - Butler, Theodore Earl and Alice (Monet), 1907-25, undated (Box 87, Folder 6)
      - Financial: stock record, 1929-51 (Box 87, Folder 7)
      - Memorabilia, 1929, undated (Box 87, Folder 8)
      - Wedding: clipping and invitation, 1902 (Box 87, Folder 9)
    - Hale, Philip Leslie (1865-1931)
      - Biographical materials and memorabilia
        - Biographical sketches and genealogy, 1932-77, undated (Box 88, Folder 1)
        - Biographical article: "Philip Leslie Hale: His Life" by Rob Leith, undated (Box 88, Folder 2)
        - Death
          - Arrangements and funeral, 1931 (Box 88, Folder 3)
          - Obituaries, 1931 (Box 88, Folder 4)
        - Financial
          - General, 1931 (Box 88, Folder 5)
          - Estate checkbook, 1931 (Box 88, Folder 6)
        - Memorabilia, 1865-1933, undated (Box 88, Folder 7)
        - Papers at Archives of American Art, 1964-75, undated (Box 88, Folder 8)
        - Scrapbook compiled circa 1931 (containing items circa 1867-1931) (Box 88, Folder 9)
      - Artwork
        - General and clippings, 1908-87, undated (Box 89, Folder 1)
        - Correspondence, 1908-88, undated (Box 89, Folder 2-4)
        - Exhibitions
          - General, 1910-75, undated (Box 89, Folder 5)
          - Memorial Exhibition, Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, 1931 (Box 89, Folder 6)
          - Vose Galleries, Boston, 1966 (Box 89, Folder 7)
          - Vose Galleries, Boston, 1988 (Box 89, Folder 8)
        - Lists of paintings and drawings, 1930, 1965,undated (Box 89, Folder 9)
        - Notes, miscellaneous, undated (Box 89, Folder 10)
        - Photographs of paintings and drawings, 1980, undated (Box 89, Folder 11)
        - Photographs of Memorial Exhibition, Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, 1931 (Box 89, Folder 12)
      - Correspondence, outgoing
        - Hales, miscellaneous, 1875-1902 (Box 90, Folder 1)
        - Hale, Edward Everett [father], 1873-1908 (Box 90, Folder 2-7)
        - Hale, Ellen Day [sister], 1873-1930, undated (Box 90, Folder 3-12)
        - Hale, Emily (Perkins) [mother], 1873-1902 (Box 90, Folder 13-15)
        - Hale, Lilian (Westcott) [wife]
          - 1901 (Box 90, Folder 16-17)
          - 1902-30, undated (Box 91, Folder 1-12)
        - Hale, Nancy [daughter]
          - circa 1910-1930 (Box 91, Folder 13-17)
          - (including some typed copies) 1930 (cont'd)-31, undated (Box 92, Folder 1-6)
        - Hardin, Taylor Scott [son-in-law], 1929-30 (Box 92, Folder 7)
        - Westcott, Harriet (Clark) [mother-in-law], 1907, 1918, 1928 (Box 92, Folder 8)
        - Miscellaneous, 1895, 1923, undated (Box 92, Folder 9)
      - Correspondence, incoming
        - Almy, Frederic, 1917-20 (Box 92, Folder 10)
        - Butler, Theodore Earl, 1897-1906, undated (Box 92, Folder 11)
        - Fenway Studios maids, 1929, 1931 (Box 92, Folder 12)
        - Hardin, Taylor Scott [son-in-law], 1928-31 (Box 92, Folder 13)
        - Presbitero, Katherine Kinsella, 1930 (Box 92, Folder 14)
        - Westcott, Harriet (Clark) [mother-in-law], 1928 (Box 92, Folder 15)
        - Whitman, Walt [typescript], undated (Box 92, Folder 16)
        - Miscellaneous, 1898-1931, undated (Box 92, Folder 17)
      - Condolence letters
        - To Lilian (Westcott) Hale, 1931 (Box 92, Folder 18-24)
        - To Nancy Hale, 1931 (Box 92, Folder 25)
      - Speeches and writings
        - Notes, miscellaneous, undated (Box 93, Folder 1)
        - Speeches
          - Clippings and publicity, 1920, undated (Box 93, Folder 2)
          - History of Art, student notes by Ann Hunt, 1928-29 (Box 93, Folder 3-4)
          - Painting, undated
            - Botticelli, Ghirlandaijo, Lippi (Box 93, Folder 5)
            - Cave Dwellers, Egyptian, Syrian (Box 93, Folder 6)
            - Chinese and Japanese (Box 93, Folder 7)
            - Cennini (Box 93, Folder 8)
            - Copley and Stuart (Box 93, Folder 9)
            - da Vinci (Box 93, Folder 10)
            - The English School (Box 93, Folder 11)
            - Gallery talks (Box 93, Folder 12)
            - Giotto (Box 93, Folder 13)
            - Grecian Painting (Box 93, Folder 14)
            - How to Paint (Box 93, Folder 15)
            - Impressionism (Box 93, Folder 16)
            - Impressionism and Post-Impressionism (Box 93, Folder 17)
            - Masaccio and Mantegna (Box 93, Folder 18)
            - Modernists I (Box 93, Folder 19)
            - Modernists II (Box 93, Folder 20)
            - Raphael (Box 93, Folder 21)
            - Titian (Box 93, Folder 22)
            - The Van Eycks (Box 93, Folder 23)
          - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 93, Folder 24)
        - Writings
          - Articles, 1896-1930 (Box 93, Folder 25)
          - Correspondence, 1930-47 (Box 93, Folder 26)
          - Jan Vermeer of Delft (1913; second edition, 1937): publicity, reviews, and essay by Ralph T. Hale, 1913, 1937 (Box 93, Folder 27)
          - Notes on [Abel] Fullum ("Yankee Handyman"), undated (Box 93, Folder 28)
          - Poems, undated (Box 93, Folder 29)
    - Hale, Lilian (Westcott) (1880-1963) [Mrs. Philip Leslie]
      - Biographical materials and memorabilia
        - Address book and births and deaths record book, undated (Box 94, Folder 1)
        - Award and certificate, 1931, undated (Box 94, Folder 2)
        - Biographical sketches, 1946-59, undated (Box 94, Folder 3)
        - Calling cards and stationary, undated (Box 94, Folder 4)
        - Christmas cards, 1923, undated (Box 94, Folder 5)
        - Christmas card lists, 1948-63 (Box 94, Folder 6)
        - Clippings, 1932-49, undated (Box 94, Folder 7)
        - Death, will, 1959, 1963 (Box 94, Folder 8)
        - Financial, 1925-28 (Box 94, Folder 9)
        - Garden, undated (Box 94, Folder 10)
        - Household business, 1913-63, undated (Box 94, Folder 11-13)
        - Passport, 1933 (Box 94, Folder 14)
        - Memorabilia, miscellaneous, 1885-1937, undated (Box 94, Folder 15-17)
        - Notebooks, miscellaneous, undated (Box 94, Folder 18)
        - Party lists, undated (Box 94, Folder 19)
        - Wedding of Nancy Hale and Taylor Scott Hardin, 1928 (Box 94, Folder 20)
      - Artwork
        - General and clippings, 1897-1983, undated (Box 95, Folder 1)
        - Clippings scrapbook, 1908-51 (Box 95, Folder 2-5)
        - Bookplate for Edith Davies Kingsbury, 1895-97 (Box 95, Folder 6)
        - Correspondence, 1895-1987, undated (Box 95, Folder 7-14)
        - Exhibitions
          - 1908-81, undated (Box 96, Folder 1-2)
          - University of Virginia Museum tea, 1960? (Box 96, Folder 3)
          - Memorial exhibitions
            - Lists of works, 1965-66, undated (Box 96, Folder 4)
            - Arrangements, 1963-66, undated (Box 96, Folder 5)
            - Correspondence, 1964-66, undated (Box 96, Folder 6)
            - Clippings and publicity, 1965-66 (Box 96, Folder 7)
        - Lists
          - Paintings (by title of work), 1926-47 (Box 96, Folder 8)
          - Sales (by title of work), 1908-46 (Box 96, Folder 9)
          - Sales, 1908-46, undated (Box 96, Folder 10)
          - Exhibitions (by title of work)
            - Typescript, 1908-31 (Box 96a, Folder 1)
            - Draft, 1908-31 (Box 96a, Folder 2-7)
          - "Nor listed or did not exhibit" (Box 96a, Folder 8)
          - Drawings (by title of work), 1919-29 (Box 97, Folder 1)
        - Notes on press coverage (Box 97, Folder 2-2a)
        - Portrait prices, 1928-29, undated (Box 97, Folder 3)
        - Photographs
          - List of distribution of photographs of works, 1926-37 (Box 97, Folder 4)
          - Drawings, 1917, undated (Box 97, Folder 5)
          - Paintings, 1915, undated (Box 97, Folder 6)
          - Portraits, undated
            - Sons-in-law, undated (Box 97, Folder 7)
            - Great-granddaughters, undated (Box 97, Folder 8)
            - Grandsons, undated (Box 97, Folder 9)
            - Lilian W. Hale (self-portrait), undated (Box 97, Folder 10)
            - Nancy Hale (daughter), undated (Box 97, Folder 11)
            - Harriet C. Westcott (mother), undated (Box 97, Folder 12)
            - Adults
              - Identified/titled works, undated (Box 97, Folder 13)
              - Unidentified/untitled works, undated (Box 97, Folder 14)
            - Children
              - Identified/titled works, undated (Box 97, Folder 15)
              - Unidentified/untitled works, undated (Box 97, Folder 16)
          - Negatives, undated (Box 97, Folder 17)
          - Slides, undated (Box 97, Folder 18)
      - Correspondence, outgoing
        - Arnold, Helen (Green), 1959-63 (Box 98, Folder 1)
        - Clements, Gabrielle, 1916, undated (Box 98, Folder 2)
        - Hale, Edward Everett [father-in-law], 1902-09 (Box 98, Folder 3-4)
        - Hale, Ellen Day [sister-in-law], 1904-39, undated (Box 98, Folder 5-18)
        - Hale, Emily Perkins [mother-in-law], 1902-13 (Box 98, Folder 19)
        - Hale, Nancy [daughter]
          - 1914-36 (Box 98, Folder 20-24)
          - 1937-49 (Box 99, Folder 1-16)
          - 1950-62, undated (Box 100, Folder 1-4)
        - Hale, Philip Leslie [husband], 1911-30, undated (Box 100, Folder 5)
        - Hardin, Rosalie [mother of son-in-law #1], 1927 (Box 100, Folder 6)
        - Hardin, Taylor Scott [son-in-law #1], 1931-44?, n.d. (Box 100, Folder 7)
        - Littell, Anna (Westcott) [sister], 1907-34, undated (Box 100, Folder 8)
        - Wertenbaker, Charles [son-in-law #2], 1936, 1938 (Box 100, Folder 9)
        - Wertenbaker, Lael [second? wife of Charles Wertenbaker], 1946-47 (Box 100, Folder 10)
        - Wertenbaker, William [grandson], 1948-49 (Box 100, Folder 11)
        - Westcotts/Littells, 1929, n. d. (Box 100, Folder 12)
        - Westcott, Edward G. [father], 1887-89, undated (Box 100, Folder 13)
        - Westcott, Harriet (Clarke) [mother] and Anna (Westcott) Littell [sister],1906-32, undated (Box 100, Folder 14)
        - Westcott, Harriet (Clarke) [mother], 1900-31, undated (Box 100, Folder 15)
        - Miscellaneous, 1919-63, undated (Box 100, Folder 16)
      - Correspondence, incoming
        - Agassiz, Mabel, 1949-55 (Box 100, Folder 17)
        - Arnold, Helen (Green), 1947-59 (Box 100, Folder 18)
        - Baxter, Molly Upson, 1902-47 (Box 100, Folder 19-20)
        - Bowers, Fredson [son-in-law #3], 1941-59 (Box 100, Folder 21)
        - Brooks, Grace, 1920, 1943-50 (Box 100, Folder 22)
        - Brown, Harold P., 1908, 1933, 1937 (Box 100, Folder 23)
        - Butler, Marthe Monet and Theodore Earl, 1904-35 (Box 100, Folder 24)
        - Cantacuzene, F. Anne, 1924, 1929, undated (Box 100, Folder 25)
        - Clements, Gabrielle, 1918-45 (Box 100, Folder 26)
        - Farnsworth, Lucy, 1924-29, undated (Box 100, Folder 27)
        - Hansell, Harriet Ann (Littell) "Hal" [niece], 1934-63, undated (Box 100, Folder 28)
        - Hardin, Mark [grandson] and nurses, 1934-61, undated (Box 100, Folder 29)
        - Hardin, Rosalie [mother of son-in-law #1] and Mark [grandson], 1927-48, undated (Box 100, Folder 30-31)
        - Hardin, Taylor Scott [son-in-law #1]
          - 1927-34 (Box 100, Folder 32-33)
          - 1935-55, undated (Box 101, Folder 1)
        - Hinkle, Beatrice, 1943 (Box 101, Folder 2)
        - Kennedy, Edith, 1917-28, undated (Box 101, Folder 3)
        - Larkin, Ruth, Oliver "Pete," and "Little Pete," 1937, 1948, undated (Box 101, Folder 4)
        - Lincoln, Agnes, 1938?-51?, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 5)
        - Littell, Anna (Westcott) [sister], 1900-63, undated (Box 101, Folder 6-15)
        - Littell, Elton [brother-in-law], 1944-61, undated (Box 101, Folder 16)
        - Loomis, Ellen
          - 1911-45 (Box 101, Folder 17)
          - 1946-55, undated (Box 102, Folder 1-2)
        - McFadden, Frances, 1943?, undated (Box 102, Folder 3)
        - Monet, Alice, 1904 (Box 102, Folder 4)
        - Nickerson, Beatrice, 1933-36, undated (Box 102, Folder 5)
        - Perkins, Elizabeth (Nowell) and Edna, 1940-57 (Box 102, Folder 6)
        - Sarton, Mabel and May, 1944-53 (Box 102, Folder 7)
        - Wertenbaker, Charles Christian [son-in-law #2], 1935-46 (Box 102, Folder 8)
        - Wertenbaker, Lael [second? wife of son-in-law #2], 1944-50 (Box 102, Folder 9)
        - Wertenbaker, William [grandson] and nurses, 1942-57, undated (Box 102, Folder 10-11)
        - Westcott, Edward G. [father], 1887 (Box 102, Folder 12)
        - Westcott, Harriet (Clarke) [mother], 1900-32, undated (Box 102, Folder 13-17)
        - White, Eliza Orne, 1934-46 (Box 102, Folder 18)
        - Miscellaneous re engagement, 1902 (Box 102, Folder 19)
        - Miscellaneous, A-Z, 1909-62, undated (Box 102, Folder 20)
        - Miscellaneous, unidentified, 1919-58, undated (Box 102, Folder 21)
      - Condolence to Nancy Hale, 1963-64 (Box 103, Folder 1-6)
      - Diaries
        - Notes on visits to London museums, 1904 (Box 104, Folder 1)
        - Notes after death of Philip Leslie Hale, Jan-Jun 1931 (Box 104, Folder 2)
        - 1932-1933, 1936-39, 1941-49, 1952-62 (Box 104, Folder 3-12)
    - Hale, Robert Beverly (1869-95) "Robbie"
      - Biographical materials and memorabilia
        - Birthday book, 1880 (Box 105, Folder 1)
        - Education
          - Miscellaneous notebooks, 1882, undated (Box 105, Folder 2)
          - Roxbury Latin School, 1883-87, undated (Box 105, Folder 3)
          - Harvard College
            - General, 1887-91 (Box 105, Folder 4)
            - Chemistry 1 notebook, 1890 (Box 105, Folder 5)
            - Themes, 1887-90 (Box 105, Folder 6)
        - Memorial Library, Matunuck, RI, 1897-1967 (Box 105, Folder 7)
        - Memorabilia, 1870-94, undated (Box 105, Folder 8)
        - Scrapbook: "R.B. Hale's and J.F. Gray's Autographs of Prominent Females," 1884-85, undated (Box 105, Folder 9)
      - Correspondence, outgoing
        - Hale, Edward Everett [father], 1873-95 (Box 105, Folder 10-12)
        - Hale, Edward Everett and Emily (Perkins) [parents], 1892 (Box 105, Folder 13)
        - Hale, Ellen Day [sister], 1877-95, undated (Box 105, Folder 14-15)
        - Hale, Emily (Perkins) [mother], 1877-95, undated (Box 105, Folder 16)
        - Hale, Lucretia and Susan [aunts], 1890, 1892 (Box 105, Folder 17)
        - Hale brothers, 1890, undated (Box 105, Folder 18)
      - Correspondence: letters of introduction, 1894-95, undated (Box 105, Folder 19)
      - Writings
        - Diaries
          - 1883(?) (Box 106, Folder 1)
          - "Journal of R.B. Hale and G.W. Lee on a journey to the White Mts. on foot," Sep 1886 (Box 106, Folder 2)
          - 1887 (Box 106, Folder 3)
        - Correspondence
          - General, 1893-95 (Box 106, Folder 4)
          - Letters of acceptance, 1891-95 (Box 106, Folder 5-6)
          - Refusals, 1891-95 (Box 106, Folder 7-9)
        - List of articles by R.B. Hale, 27 Apr 1892 (Box 106, Folder 10)
        - Poems, 1892-96, undated (Box 106, Folder 11)
        - Scrapbook "Literary Criticisms in Commonwealth," 1892-94 (Box 106, Folder 12)
        - Stories and essays, 1895-96, undated (Box 106, Folder 13)
        - Notebook, undated (Box 106, Folder 14)
        - Volume: Six Stories and Some Verses. (Boston: J.M. Bowles Publisher, 1896) (Box 106, Folder 15)
  - Generations V and VI